United States Strategic Bombing Survey: [Reports] (Pacific War)
Science, Technology & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Military Studies (Reports 61-108)
  - Military Analysis Division (Reports 61-71a)
    - The Seventh and Eleventh Air Forces in the War Against Japan. Dates of Survey: 7 December 1941-15 August 1945. [Washington]: Military Analysis Division, May 1947., vii, 55 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 70)
    - The Fifth Air Force in the War Against Japan, June 1947. [Washington]: Military Analysis Division, 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/47046597; vi, 114 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 71)
    - Air Campaigns of the Pacific War, July 1947. Washington: Military Analysis Division; For sale by the U.S. Government Printing Office, 1947., vi, 75 p.: illus., tables, maps (some folded). (Report 71a)
  - Naval Analysis Division (Reports 72-89)
    - Interrogations of Japanese Officials. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division, 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/46026882; 2 v. (xv, 576 p.): illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Vol. 1 includes "List of Interrogations" and "Index of Major Battles and Operations and Japanese Officials"; vol. 2 includes "Japanese Notes of Battles" and "Biographies of Interrogated Japanese Officials." "OPNAV-P-03-100" (Report 72)
    - The Campaigns of the Pacific War. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division; [For sale by the U.S. Government Printing Office, 1946]., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/46027588; xv, 395 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 73)
    - The Reduction of Wake Island, 1 July 1946. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division, Marshalls-Gilberts-New Britain Party; [For sale by the U.S. Government Printing Office], 1946., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/48046134; iii, 129 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps. (Report 74)
    - The Allied Campaign Against Rabaul, 1 September 1946. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division, Marshalls-Gilberts-New Britain Party; [For sale by the U.S. Government Printing Office], 1946., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/46027928; ix, 273 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps. (Report 75)
    - The American Campaign Against Wotje, Maloelap, Mille, and Jaluit. Dates of Survey: 5 October 1945-2 November 1945. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division, May 1947., iv, 375 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps. (Report 76)
    - The Reduction of Truk, February 1947. Washington: Naval Analysis Division; For sale by the U.S. Government Printing Office, 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/47032763; v, 26 p.: illus., tables, folded map. (Report 77)
    - The Offensive Mine Laying Campaign Against Japan, 1 November 1946. [Washington]: Naval Analysis Division, 1946., Catalog Record (1969 reprint): http://lccn.loc.gov/74605489; vi, 128 p.: illus., diagrams, tables, map. (Report 78)
    - Ships' bombardment of Japan--1945: Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party. [Washington: Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, 1946]., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/61034130; 12 v. in 11: illus., diagrams, tables, map (some folded). (Report 79-89)
      - Ships' bombardment of Japan--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey: Contents, Introduction, Conclusions, General Summary. [Washington: Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, 1946]., vii, 7 p.: illus., map. (Report 79)
      - Study of Kamaishi Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (A). Washington: Navy Department, April 1946., iii, 184 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Kamaishi Naval Bombardments, 14 July and 9 August 1945. Enclosure (A). (Report 80)
      - Study of Hamamatsu Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (B). Washington: Navy Department, April 1946., viii, 318 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Hamamatsu Naval Bombardment, 29-30 July 1945. Enclosure (B). (Report 81)
      - Study of Hitachi Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (C). Washington: Navy Department, April 1946., viii, 319 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Hitachi Naval Bombardment, 17-18 July 1945. Enclosure (C). (Report 82)
      - Study of Hakodate Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (D). Washington: Navy Department, April 1946., iii, 39 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Hakodate Naval Air Strikes, 14-15 July 1945. Enclosure (D). (Report 83)
      - Study of Muroran Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (E). Washington: Navy Department, April 1946., iii, 140 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Muroran Naval Bombardment, 15 July 1945. Enclosure (E). (Report 84)
      - Study of Shimizu Area--1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (F). Washington: Navy Department, [1946]., 1 v. (various paging): illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Shimizu Naval Bombardment, 31 July 1945. Enclosure (F). (Report 85)
      - Study of Shionomisaki Area: Ships' Bombardments of Japan, 1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (G). Study of Nojima Saki Area: Ships' Bombardments of Japan, 1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (H). Washington: Navy Department, May 1946., iii, 29 p., iii, 13 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Shionomisaki Naval Bombardment, 24-25 July 1945; Nojima Saki Naval Bombardment, 18-19 July 1945. Enclosures (G) and (H). (Report 86)
      - Comments and Data on Effectiveness of Ammunition: Ships' Bombardments of Japan, 1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (I). Comments and Data on Accuracy of Firemarms: Ships' Bombardments of Japan, 1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (J). Washington: Navy Department, May 1946., iii, 34, iii, 59 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Comments and Data on Effectiveness of Ammunition and Accuracy of Firings: Ships' Bombardments, July-August 1945. Enclosures (I) and (J). Not in LC collection. (Report 87-88)
      - Effects of Surface Bombardments on Japanese War Potential: Ships' Bombardments of Japan, 1945. Report of Ships' Bombardment Survey Party, U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey, Enclosure (K). Washington: Navy Department, May 1946., iv, 41 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Cover title: Effects of Surface Bombardments on Japanese War Potential: Ships' Bombardments, July-August 1945. Enclosure (K). (Report 89)
  - Physical Damage Division (Reports 90-96)
    - Effects of the Incendiary Bomb Attacks on Japan: A Report on Eight Cities. Dates of Survey: 3 October 1945-1 December 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, April 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/49045689; vi, 240 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 90)
    - The Effects of the Ten Thousand-Pound Bomb on Japanese Targets: A Report on Nine Incidents. Dates of Survey: 20 October-16 November 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, May 1947., vi, 230 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 91)
    - The Effects of the Atomic Bomb on Hiroshima, Japan. Dates of Survey: 14 October-26 November 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, May 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/55057769; 3 v. (v. 1: vi, 120 p.; v. 2: vi, 635 p., v. 3: v, 341 p.): illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 92)
    - Effects of the Atomic Bomb on Nagasaki, Japan. Dates of Survey: 13 October-20 November 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, June 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/55057770; 3 v. (v. 1: vi, 423 p.; v. 2: vi, 353 p., v. 3: v, 270 p.): illus., tables, diagrams, folded maps. (Report 93)
    - The Effects of the Four-Thousand-Pound Bomb on Japanese Targets: A Report on Five Incidents. Dates of Survey: 19 October-16 November 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, May 1947., vi, 285 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 94)
    - Effects of Two Thousand, One Thousand, and Five Hundred Pound Bombs on Japanese Targets: A Report on Eight Incidents. Dates of Survey: 19 October-20 November 1945. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, April 1947., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/52060971; iv, 280 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 95)
    - A Report on Physical Damage in Japan: Summary Report. [Washington]: Physical Damage Division, June 1947., v, 225 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 96)
  - G-2 Division (Reports 97-108)
    - Japanese Military and Naval Intelligence Division. Dates of Survey: 1 November 1945 through 1 February 1946. Washington: Japanese Intelligence Section, G-2; [For sale by the] U.S. Government Printing Office, April 1946., vi, 127 p.: illus., tables, diagrams. (Report 97)
    - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, 1946., Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/47031641; 11 v.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps.; "OPNAV P23-V2-120." (Report 98-108)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part One, Comprehensive Report. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-1 May 1946. Washington: Photographic Intelligence Section; [For sale by the] U.S. Government Printing Office, August 1946., vii, 47 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps. (Report 98)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Two, Airfields. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 24 p.: illus., tables (some folded). (Report 99)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Three, Computed Bomb Plotting. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-1 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 44 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded). (Report 100)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Four, Urban Area Analysis. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 31 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps. (Report 101)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Five, Camouflage, Concealment, and Deception. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 24 p.: illus., maps (one folded).; Contains "vectograph exhibits," with Polaroid 3-D viewer in pocket on last page following text. (Report 102)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Six, Shipping. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-1 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 19 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 103)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Seven, Electronics. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 40 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 104)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Eight, Beach Intelligence. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-1 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 24 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 105)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Nine, Coast and Anti-Aircraft Artillery. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 20 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded).; Contains "vectograph exhibits," with Polaroid 3-D viewer in pocket on last page following text. (Report 106)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Ten, Roads and Railroads. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-1 March 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 10 p.: illus., tables, diagrams, maps (one folded). (Report 107)
      - Evaluation of Photographic Intelligence in the Japanese Homeland. Part Eleven, Industrial Analysis. Dates of Survey: 7 October 1945-15 May 1946. [Washington]: Photographic Intelligence Section, June 1946., 1 v. (various paging): illus., tables, diagrams, maps (some folded).; Contains "vectograph exhibits," with Polaroid 3-D viewer in pocket on last page following text. (Report 108)
Further Reading
Biddle, Tami Davis. Rhetoric and Reality in Air Warfare: The Evolution of British and American Ideas about Strategic Bombing, 1914-1945.
Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, c2002. 406 p.
LC Call Number: UG705.G7B54 2002
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2001036865
Bombing Civilians: A Twentieth-Century History. Edited by Yuki Tanaka and Marilyn B. Young.
New York: New Press: Distributed by W.W. Norton, 2009. 291 p.
LC Call Number: D431.B66 2009
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2008027814
Grayling, A. C. Among the Dead Cities: The History and Moral Legacy of the WWII Bombing of Civilians in Germany and Japan.
New York: Walker and Co., 2006. 361 p.
LC Call Number: D790.2.G73 2006
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2005058597
A Guide to the Reports of The United States Strategic Bombing Survey. Edited by Gordon Daniels.
London: Offices of the Royal Historical Society, University College London, 1981. 115 p.
LC Call Number: D785.U63 Suppl.
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/82187771
Knell, Hermann. To Destroy a City: Strategic Bombing and Its Human Consequences in World War II.
Cambridge, Mass.: Da Capo, 2003. 373 p.
LC Call Number: D757.9.W8K58 2003
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2003544951
MacIsaac, David. Strategic Bombing in World War Two: The Story of the United States Strategic Bombing Survey.
New York: Garland Pub. Co., 1976. 231 p.
LC Call Number: D785.U573M3
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/75027037
Ross, Stewart Halsey. Strategic Bombing by the United States in World War II: The Myths and the Facts.
Jefferson, N.C.: McFarland & Co., c2003. 244 p.
LC Call Number: D785.U57R67 2003
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2002014698
Sebald, Winfried Georg. On the Natural History of Destruction. Translated by Anthea Bell.
New York: Modern Library, 2004. 202 p.
LC Call Number: PT405.S4313 2004
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2004269961
Swift, Daniel. Bomber County: the Poetry of a Lost Pilot's War.
New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, c2010. 269 p.
LC Call Number: PR605.W66S95 2010
Catalog Record: http://lccn.loc.gov/2010023402